We're at a critical moment.
我们正处在一个关键时刻。
Our leaders,
我们的领导者，
some of our great institutions
一些重要的机构
are failing us.
正在辜负我们的期待。
Why?
为什么？
In some cases, it's because they're bad
在某些案例中，因为他们心怀不轨
or unethical,
或违背了职业道德，
but often, they've taken us to the wrong objectives.
但通常是因为他们把我们 带向了错误的目标。
And this is unacceptable.
而这是让人无法接受的。
This has to stop.
这样的情况应当到此为止。
How are we going to correct these wrongs?
我们该如何纠正这些错误？
How are we going to choose the right course?
我们该如何选择正确的道路？
It's not going to be easy.
这并非易事。
For years, I've worked with talented teams
多年来我一直在与杰出的团队共事，
and they've chosen the right objectives and the wrong objectives.
他们或在正确的道路上前进， 或选错了目标而事与愿违。
Many have succeeded, others of them have failed.
许多目标成功达成了，有些则遭遇了失败。
And today I'm going to share with you
今天我要和你分享的是
what really makes a difference --
真正能够带来改变的事情——
that's what's crucial,
即问题的关键所在，
how and why
他们为何以及如何
they set meaningful and audacious goals,
制定出有意义的、大胆的目标，
the right goals for the right reasons.
即有正当理由的，正确的目标。
Let's go back to 1975.
让我们回到1975年。
Yep, this is me.
没错，这就是我。
I've got a lot to learn, I'm a computer engineer,
当时我是个计算机工程师， 还有很多东西要学。
I've got long hair,
我留着长发，
but I'm working under Andy Grove,
在安迪 · 葛洛夫手下工作，
who's been called the greatest manager of his or any other era.
在任何时代，他都 称得上是最伟大的管理者。
Andy was a superb leader and also a teacher,
安迪不仅是一流的领导者，也是一名导师。
and he said to me, "John, it almost doesn't matter what you know.
他曾对我说：“约翰， 你所知道的东西并不重要，
Execution is what matters the most."
执行才是最重要的。”
And so Andy invented a system called "Objectives and Key Results."
安迪发明了一个系统， 称为“目标和关键成果法”。
It kind of rolls off the tongue, doesn't it?
听起来是不是有点绕口？
And it's all about excellent execution.
其核心全在于出色的执行。
So here's a classic video from the 1970s
以下是一段1970年代的经典录像，
of professor Andy Grove.
录像里出现的就是安迪 · 葛洛夫教授。
(Video) Andy Grove: The two key phrases of the management by objective systems
（录像）安迪 · 葛洛夫： 这种目标管理的两个关键词是
are the objectives and the key results, and they match the two purposes.
“目标”和“关键成果”， 它们分别对应着两个目的：
The objective is the direction.
目标是方向，
The key results have to be measured,
关键成果需要得到评估，
but at the end you can look and without any argument say,
但是最终结果显而易见，根本不需要出现
"Did I do that, or did I not do that?" Yes. No. Simple.
“我做了这个吗，或者根本没做？” 那样的争论，是或否，就是这么简单。
John Doerr: That's Andy.
约翰 · 杜尔：这就是安迪。
Yes. No. Simple.
是或否，就是这么简单。
Objectives and Key Results,
目标和关键成果法
or OKRs,
也称为OKRs，
are a simple goal-setting system
是一个简单的目标制定方法。
and they work for organizations, they work for teams,
它适用于组织还有团队，
they even work for individuals.
甚至也适用于个人。
The objectives are what you want to have accomplished.
目标就是你想实现的事情，
The key results are how I'm going to get that done.
关键成果是你要如何达成目标。
Objectives. Key results.
目标，以及关键成果，
What and how.
就是要做什么和如何实现。
But here's the truth:
但真实的情况是：
many of us are setting goals wrong,
我们中有许多人都制定了错误的目标，
and most of us are not setting goals at all.
大多数人甚至完全不设定目标。
A lot of organizations set objectives and meet them.
许多组织机构设定目标并努力实现它们。
They ship their sales, they introduce their new products,
这些组织发货，研发新产品，
they make their numbers,
他们不断获得收益，
but they lack a sense of purpose to inspire their teams.
但缺少激励团队的使命感。
So how do you set these goals the right way?
那么该如何正确地设定目标呢？
First, you must answer the question, "Why?"
首先你必须回答一个问题：“为什么？”
Why?
为什么这么问？
Because truly transformational teams
因为真正变革型的团队
combine their ambitions to their passion and to their purpose,
都会将自己的雄心、 热情和目标结合到一起。
and they develop a clear and compelling sense of why.
他们很清楚为何要做，且理由令人信服。
I want to tell you a story.
我想要告诉大家一个故事，
I work with a remarkable entrepreneur.
有一位与我共事的出色的企业家，
Her name is Jini Kim.
她的名词是金基妮(Jini Kim)。
She runs a company called Nuna.
她运营着一家公司，叫做Nuna。
Nuna is a health care data company.
这是一家健康护理数据公司。
And when Nuna was founded,
公司初创时，
they used data to serve the health needs of lots of workers at large companies.
他们使用数据为大企业的 很多员工提供健康服务。
And then two years into the company's life,
公司成立两年后，
the federal government issued a proposal
联邦政府发布了一项提案，
to build the first ever cloud database for Medicaid.
要成立首个用于医疗救助 制度的云数据库。
Now, you'll remember that Medicaid is that program
你们知道医疗救助制度
that serves 70 million Americans,
为7千万美国人服务，
our poor, our children
包括贫困人群，儿童，
and people with disabilities.
以及残障人士。
Nuna at the time was just 15 people
Nuna公司在当时只有15个人，
and this database had to be built in one year,
这个数据库要在一年内建成，
and they had a whole set of commitments that they had to honor,
他们有一系列承诺需要履行。
and frankly, they weren't going to make very much money on the project.
坦白讲，这个项目 并不能让他们大赚一笔。
This was a bet-your-company moment,
这是赌上公司的时刻，
and Jini seized it.
而基妮把握住了它。
She jumped at the opportunity. She did not flinch.
她扑向了这个机会，她没有退缩。
Why?
为什么？
Well, it's a personal why.
这事关个人原因。
Jini's younger brother Kimong has autism.
基妮的弟弟津孟(Kimong)患有自闭症，
And when he was seven,
在七岁时，
he had his first grand mal seizure
他第一次发病
at Disneyland.
是在迪士尼乐园。
He fell to the ground. He stopped breathing.
他倒在地上，停止了呼吸。
Jini's parents are Korean immigrants.
基妮的父母都是韩裔移民，
They came to the country with limited resources
他们身无长物来到这个国家，
speaking little English,
也不太会讲英语，
so it was up to Jini to enroll her family in Medicaid.
所以只能靠基妮 帮家人加入医疗救助系统。
She was nine years old.
她当时只有九岁。
That moment defined her mission,
这个重大时刻决定了她的使命，
and that mission became her company,
而这项使命成就了她公司，
and that company bid on, won and delivered on that contract.
这家公司竞标，赢得并实现了这个合同。
Here's Jini to tell you why.
让基妮来告诉你她这样做的原因。
(Video) Jini Kim: Medicaid saved my family from bankruptcy,
（视频）金基妮：医疗救助 使我的家庭免于破产，
and today it provides for Kimong's health and for millions of others.
如今它为津孟和其他 数百万患者提供健康服务。
Nuna is my love letter to Medicaid.
Nuna是我给医疗救助的一封情书。
Every row of data is a life
每一条数据都是一个生命，
whose story deserves to be told with dignity.
它的故事需要有尊严地被讲述。
JD: And Jini's story tells us
约翰 · 杜尔：基妮的故事告诉我们，
that a compelling sense of why can be the launchpad for our objectives.
一种极具说服力的原因 能够成为目标的发射平台。
Remember, that's what we want to have accomplished.
要记得，这是我们想要达成的事情。
And objectives are significant,
目标是重要的，
they're action-oriented,
它们以行动为指向，
they are inspiring,
它们激励人心，
and they're a kind of vaccine against fuzzy thinking.
是对抗纷乱思绪的一针疫苗。
You think a rockstar
你以为一个摇滚明星，
would be an unlikely user of Objectives and Key Results,
不太可能使用目标成果法，
but for years, Bono has used OKRs
但是数年以来， 博诺（Bono）通过使用OKRs
to wage a global war against poverty and disease,
掀起了一场对抗贫穷和 疾病的全球战争。
and his ONE organization has focused on two really gorgeous,
他的One组织专注在两个目标上，
audacious objectives.
它们非常棒，也非常大胆。
The first is debt relief
第一个目标
for the poorest countries in the world.
是为世界上最贫穷的国家减轻债务；
The next is universal access to anti-HIV drugs.
第二个则是普及抗艾滋病药物。
Now, why are these good objectives?
如今，这些目标完成的怎么样了？
Let's go back to our checklist.
让我们回到我们的检查清单。
Significant? Check. Concrete? Yes.
这些目标重要么？是的。 这些目标具体么？是的。
Action-oriented? Yes.
它们以行动为导向么？是的。
Inspirational?
是否激励人心？
Well, let's just listen to Bono.
还是让我们听听博诺怎么说。
(Video) Bono: So you're passionate?
（视频）博诺：你有热情么？
How passionate?
有多大热情？
What actions does your passion lead you to do?
你的热情引导出了你的什么行动？
If the heart doesn't find a perfect rhyme with the head,
如果内心找不到与大脑和谐的韵律，
then your passion means nothing.
你的热情就毫无用处。
The OKR framework cultivates the madness,
OKRs框架可以培养出疯狂的想法，
the chemistry contained inside it.
里面包含着化学火花。
It gives us an environment for risk,
它给了我们一个环境，为了风险，
for trust,
为了信任，
where failing is not a fireable offense.
在这里，失败不是可怕的犯罪。
And when you have that sort of structure and environment
当你有了这种结构和环境，
and the right people,
加上对的人，
magic is around the corner.
奇迹就会出现。
JD: I love that.
约翰 · 杜尔：我很喜欢这段话，
OKRs cultivate the madness,
OKRs培养出疯狂的想法，
and magic is right around the corner.
奇迹就会出现。
This is perfect.
这简直完美。
So with Jini we've covered the whys,
通过基妮，我们看到了原因，
with Bono the whats of goal-setting.
通过博诺，我们了解了目标设定。
Let's turn our attention to the hows.
让我们再来关注方法。
Remember, the hows are the key results.
如何做是关键结果。
That's how we meet our objectives.
这就是我们实现目标的方法。
And good results are specific and time-bound.
好的结果是明确且有时间限制的。
They're aggressive but realistic.
它们很激进但也很现实，
They're measurable, and they're verifiable.
它们可衡量也可评估，
Those are good key results.
这就是好的关键成果。
In 1999, I introduced OKRs to Google's cofounders,
1999年，我向谷歌的 联合创始人拉里和谢尔盖
Larry and Sergey.
介绍了OKRs。
Here they are, 24 years old in their garage.
这是24岁时的他们在自家的车库里。
And Sergey enthusiastically said he'd adopt them.
谢尔盖充满热情地说打算采用这个方法。
Well, not quite.
然而，确切地说，
What he really said was,
他真正说的是：
"We don't have any other way to manage this company,
“我们没有其他的方法来管理这家公司，
so we'll give it a go."
所以不如试一下。“
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And I took that as a kind of endorsement.
我将其视为某种认可。
But every quarter since then,
从那之后的每个季度，
every Googler has written down her objectives and her key results.
每一个谷歌人写下的目标和关键成果，
They've graded them,
都会得到他们的评价，
and they've published them for everyone to see.
然后公布给每个人看。
And these are not used for bonuses or for promotions.
这些内容并不被用于奖金或升职，
They're set aside.
就是摆在那里，
They're used for a higher purpose,
用于实现更高的目标——
and that's to get collective commitment
那就是获取共同责任感
to truly stretch goals.
以真正推动目标。
In 2008, a Googler, Sundar Pichai, took on an objective
在2008年，谷歌员工 桑达尔 · 皮查伊设定了一个目标，
which was to build the next generation client platform
他要为未来的网络应用
for the future of web applications --
建立下一代客户平台。
in other words, build the best browser.
换句话说，就是打造一个最好的浏览器。
He was very thoughtful about how he chose his key results.
在选择关键结果上，| 他有着非常深入的思考。
How do you measure the best browser?
如何来衡量这是最好的浏览器？
It could be ad clicks or engagement.
可以参考广告点击和用户参与度。
No. He said: numbers of users,
不，他认为是用户数量，
because users are going to decide
因为用户会决定
if Chrome is a great browser or not.
Chrome浏览器是好还是坏。
So he had this one three-year-long objective:
因此他定下了这个长达三年的目标：
build the best browser.
打造最好的浏览器。
And then every year he stuck to the same key results,
之后的每一年，他都会 专注于相同的关键成果，
numbers of users, but he upped the ante.
即用户数量，但是要求不断提高。
In the first year, his goal was 20 million users
在最初一年，他的目标是2000万用户，
and he missed it.
但并没有达成。
He got less than 10.
用户数量还不到1000万。
Second year, he raised the bar to 50 million.
第二年，他把目标提高到5000万。
He got to 37 million users.
结果用户数量达到 3700 万。
Somewhat better.
不管怎样，总算有些进步。
In the third year,
在第三年，
he upped the ante once more to a hundred million.
他再次将目标提高到1亿。
He launched an aggressive marketing campaign,
他启动了一个激进的营销活动，
broader distribution, improved the technology, and kaboom!
采用更广泛的推广手段， 改善的技术，用户数量终于爆发了！
He got 111 million users.
他获得了1.11亿用户。
Here's why I like this story,
我之所以喜欢这个故事，
not so much for the happy ending,
并不在于它有圆满的大结局，
but it shows someone carefully choosing the right objective
而是它表现出一个人 仔细选择了正确的目标，
and then sticking to it year after year after year.
并年复一年始终坚持下来。
It's a perfect story for a nerd like me.
对我这样的书呆子来说， 这简直是个完美的故事。
Now, I think of OKRs as transparent vessels
我把OKRs看做是一个透明容器，
that are made from the whats and hows of our ambitions.
它由野心勃勃的“做什么” 和“怎么做”构成。
What really matters is the why that we pour into those vessels.
真正的关键在于 放进容器中的“为什么”，
That's why we do our work.
那是我们工作的原因。
OKRs are not a silver bullet.
OKRs并非万能良药。
They're not going to be a substitute for a strong culture
它无法代替强有力的文化
or for stronger leadership,
或是强有力的领导力。
but when those fundamentals are in place, they can take you to the mountaintop.
但当这些基本元素都就位， 它们就可以带你走上巅峰。
I want you to think about your life for a moment.
现在，我希望你们 思考一下自己的生活。
Do you have the right metrics?
你是否拥有正确的衡量标准？
Take time to write down your values,
花点时间写下你认为有价值的东西，
your objectives and your key results.
你的目标和关键成果。
Do it today.
今天就行动。
If you'd like some feedback on them, you can send them to me.
如果你想获得反馈，可以将它发给我。
I'm john@whatmatters.com.
我的邮箱地址是： john@whatmatters.com
If we think of the world-changing goals
如果我们想想那些改变世界的目标，
of an Intel, of a Nuna, of Bono,
英特尔，Nuna，博诺，
of Google,
还有谷歌的目标，
they're remarkable:
它们都令人惊叹：
ubiquitous computing,
普适计算，
affordable health care, high-quality for everyone,
低价优质的全民医疗，
ending global poverty,
终结全球贫困，
access to all the world's information.
获取全球信息。
Here's the deal:
事实情况是，
every one of those goals is powered today by OKRs.
每个目标都得到了OKRs的助力。
Now, I've been called the Johnny Appleseed of OKRs
现在我被叫做OKRs播种机，
for spreading the good gospel according to Andy Grove,
将安迪 · 葛洛夫的福音传播四方。
but I want you to join me in this movement.
但是我希望你也能参与到这场运动中，
Let's fight for what it is that really matters,
让我们为真正关键的事情而奋斗，
because we can take OKRs beyond our businesses.
因为我们不仅可以 将OKRs运用到商业中，
We can take them to our families,
还可以将其用于家庭，
to our schools,
学校，
even to our governments.
甚至是政府。
We can hold those governments accountable.
我们可以让政府承担责任。
We can transform those informations.
我们可以转化这些信息。
We can get back on the right track
我们可以回到正确的轨道上——
if we can and do measure what really matters.
前提是，我们能够并且 真正去判断关键所在。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。
(Applause)
（掌声）